UNITE HERE Sidney Hillman Foundation Awards 6200/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE Sidney Hillman Foundation Awards
2007-2008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
UNITE HERE
Sidney Hillman Foundation
6200/004
1.33 cubic feet
1.3 linear ft.
Awards, DVDs, scrapbooks.
6332105
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 27, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 25, 2015
Biographical / Historical
The Sidney Hillman Foundation was named for the labor leader, Sidney Hillman (1887-1946), who was the first president of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA). Immediately after his death, his union wished to honor him with a memorial that would carry on his commitments to the lives of working people. On November 17, 1946, the General Executive Board of the ACWA voted to establish the Sidney Hillman Foundation. ACWA contributed the first $100,000 and then raised one million dollars from other organizations. In 1947, the Board of Directors issued the first grants for scholarships, research and lectures on college campuses, and for medical research at the Sidney Hillman Health Centers.
In 1950, the Foundation launched the Hillman Prize in order to promote socially-responsible journalism. Starting with awards in Book, Magazine, Newspaper, and Broadcast, the prize is now also offered in the categories of Photojournalism, Web, and Opinion and Analysis. One important note is that the Hillman Foundation changed its dating system for prizes in 1999/ 2000. The Foundation decided to name the prize for the year it was given rather than the year the work was produced, changing the pattern of the previous fifty years. This new system continues to the present. This means that in effect there are no prizes for the year 1999, but a year was not skipped in the granting of awards.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Textile workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); UNITE HERE (Organization); Sidney Hillman Foundation; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization)
6332105
- 57th Annual Awards Presentation Program, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  May 22, 2007. Award winners: David Montgomery; Thomas E. Ricks; Rukmini Maria Callimachi; Mike Stocker; Joe Amon; Douglas McGray; Spike Lee; Sam Pollard; Sam Rosenfeld; Ann Friedman; Garance Franke-Ruta; Ezra Klein; Matthew Yglesias; Harry Belafonte. 2 copies.
- 58th Annual Awards Presentation Program, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  May 27, 2008. Award winners: Faiz Shakir; Amanda Terkel; Robert Kuttner; Bill Moyers; Kathleen Hughes; Ray Ring; Charles Duhigg; Luis Sinco; David Brody; Writers Guild of America
- "The Marlboro Marine" by Luis Sinco scrapbook, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Los Angeles Times November 11, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Marlboro Marine (Box 2)
- 2008 Sidney Hillman, Foundation Awards (Box 3)
- 2008 Sidney Hillman, Foundation Awards (Box 4)
- Buying the war Clip (Box 5)
- Bill Moyers' Thank you (Box 6)
- Thinkprogress.org Video (Box 7)